Register of the Irwin Abrams Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1902-1987 (Boxes 4-13)
  - International education
    - Council for the Advancement of Experiential Learning and International Relations Program of Michigan State University, Task Force, "The Role of Experiential Learning in Cross Cultural Program,", 1978-1979
      - Report. J. Duley, "Impact of Experiential Learning on Academic Performance," Typescript, n.d. (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Continuation Committee for Creation of an International Educational Exchange, Bellagio, Italy, 1966 December 2-5
      - General. Report and memoranda (Box-folder 5: 3)
      - Preparatory documents, #1-4f and 7a and b (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Council on Student Travel (currently known as Council on International Educational Exchange), 1959-1973
      - Correspondence, 1960-1973 (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - Minutes, 1960 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      - Reports, 1959 (Box-folder 5: 7)
      - National Conference on Undergraduate Study Abroad, Pick-Congress Hotel, Chicago, Illinois. Includes pre-registration list and opening remarks, Typewritten copies, 1960 October 7-8. (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Deutsche Stiftung fur Internationale Entwicklung. Reports
      - General. Including various cultural topics, Typescript, 1974-1980. (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - "Evaluierung und Berichterstattung bei Trainingsprogrammen fur Fache- und Fuhrungskrdfte", Typescript, 1979. (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - East German education. Notes, articles, and clippings, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - German-American Conference on International Educational Exchange, Bonn, Germany., 1980 November 24-28
      See also Academic Career and Peace Organizations File, International Society for Educational, Cultural and Scientific Interchanges (Box 19, Folders 2-3).
      - General. Memoranda, notes, and delegation list (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - Reports. Including papers presented at the conference (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
    - Great Lakes Colleges Association (GLCA), 1962-1972
      - General, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - Memoranda, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box-folder 6: 6)
      - Report. "Community without Commonness," Printed copy, 1965. (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - Conference on Foreign Language and Cultural Understanding, Delaware, Ohio, and Kalamazoo, Michigan, Summary of proceedings, minutes of steering committee meeting, and reports, 1968 November 8-10, 1969 April 25-26. (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - Japan Study Program. Reports, 1979 January 10-16 (Box-folder 7: 2)
      - Near East Program. Report from Beirut, Lebanon., 1969 (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - Polish Seminar. Report, 1974 (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - Yugoslav Seminars
        - Comprehensive report, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 7: 5)
        - Fifth Yugoslav-American Seminar, Reports, programs, and other notes, 1960. (Box-folder 7: 6)
        - American-Yugoslav Seminars, 1970
          - Memoranda and notes (Box-folder 7: 7)
          - Reports. Includes papers presented at the seminar (Box-folder 7: 8-9)
        - American-Yugoslav Seminar, 1971
          - General. Proposal for seminar and program log (Box-folder 7: 10)
          - Reports. Includes papers presented at the seminar (Box-folder 7: 11-12)
    - International Education Act, 1966-1969
      - General. Report on study abroad, Congressional testimony, and mailing list, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 7: 14)
      - Memoranda, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - Notes, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - International Education Act Conference, Des Plaines, Illinois, Reports, correspondence, and memoranda, 1967 May 3. (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - International Society for Education, Cultural, and Scientific Interchanges (ISECSI)
      - General. By-laws of ISECSI, address list, and objective statement (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - Bulletins, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 8: 5-8)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 8: 9)
      - Memoranda, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - Newsletters, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - Pamphlets, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - Reports. Treasurer's report and membership report (Box-folder 8: 14)
    - Miscellaneous. Pamphlets and articles (Box-folder 6: 8-9)
    - Printed matter
      - Breitenbach, Diether and Dieter Danckwortt, Probleme der Ausbildung und Anpassung von Praktikanten aus Entwicklungslandern, 1966 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst Bonn
        - Auslandische Stipendiaten in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 2)
        - Deutsche Partner in der internationalen wissenschaftlichen Zusammenarbeit, 1979 (Box-folder 9: 3)
        - Die Forderung afrikanischer Studenten durch den DAAD, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 4)
        - Franzosische Germanistikstudenten, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 5)
        - Studienerfolg und Studienerfolganalyse auslandischer Studenten in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - Gechter, Heinz A., Die Fortbilding deutscher Landwirte in den USA, 1966 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - Klein, Paul, Urteile junger franzosischer Arbeitnehmer uber Deutsche vor, wahrend und nach einem einjahrigen Arbeitsaufenthalt in Deutschland, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 8)
      - Robinsohn, Saul B., and U. Chaim Schatzer, Judische Geschichte in deutschen Geschichtslehrbuchern, 1963 (Box-folder 9: 9)
      - Torke, Hans-Joachim, Die russische Geschichte in den Lehrbuchern der hoheren Schulen der Bundesrepublik Deutschland, 1962 (Box-folder 9: 10)
      - Die USA und Deutschland: Zeitgeschichtliche Fragen, Papers and reports of the third amerikanisch-deutschen Historikertagung, Braunschweig, Germany, 1960 June 25-28 (Box-folder 9: 11)
      - Vente, Rolf E., Entwicklunglander, Entwicklungshilfe, Ausbildungshilfe, 1966 (Box-folder 9: 12)
      - Winter, Gerhard, Bedingungsanalyse internationaler Kommunikation und Einstellungsanderung, 1980 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - United States' image in German high school textbooks. Articles, correspondence and report written by Irwin Abrams, 1961. (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Nobel Peace Prize
    - General (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Articles, 1945-1987 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Clippings, 1961-1989 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Interview. Carl von Ossietzky, Mimeographed copy, 1938. (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Report. "Report on the Round Table of Institutions Which Have Been Awarded the Nobel Peace Prize,", 1978 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Peace
    - General. Correspondence and articles, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Bulletins
      - "The Aims of the Peace Society of Norway,", 1983 (Box-folder 10: 9)
      - "Consortium on Peace Research, Education and Development" (COPRED), 1979-1984 (Box-folder 10: 10)
      - "Peace in Action,", 1985 (Box-folder 10: 11)
      - "Peace Studies Institute,", 1986-1987 (Box-folder 10: 12)
    - Clippings, 1938-1982 (Box-folder 10: 13)
    - Newsletter. The Arbitrator, 1937 (Box-folder 10: 14)
    - Pamphlets, 1902-1957 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
    - Reports
      - "Organized Efforts in the United States Toward Peace,", 1936 (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - "The Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships: Common Concerns, Uncommon Perspectives,", 1976 (Box-folder 11: 4)
      - "Bericht uber die erste Tagung des Weltkongresses der Friedenskrdfte," Moscow, Soviet Union, 1973 October 25-31 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Socialism. Pamphlets (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Tourism
    - Printed matter, 1959-1978
      - Alexander von Humboldt-Stiftung, Sprache als ifMttler, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 7)
      - Psychologisches Institut der Universitdt Hamburg, Die junge Elite: Asiens und Afrikas als Gast und Schuler Europas, 1959 August (Box-folder 11: 8)
      - Studienkreis fur Tourismus e.V., Starnberg, Germany
        - Dienen Urlaubsreisen der Volkerverstandigung?, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 9)
        - Landerkundliche Anregungen und Informationen bei Auslandsreisen, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 10)
        - Wie werden Deutsche im Ausland gesehen?, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 11)
        - Untersuchung zur psychologischen Wirkungsweise von Sympathie-Magazinen bei Fernreisenden, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 12)
        - Jugendaustausch innerhalb einer Stadtepartnerschaft, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 13)
        - Mitglieder des Studienkreises fur Tourismus e.V., 1978 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Reports
      - Alexander von Humboldt Foundation, 1953-1978 (Box-folder 12: 2)
      - Studienkreis fur Tourismus e.V., Arbeitsbericht 1977 des Studienkreises fur Tourismus e.V. (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - United Nations
    - Printed matter
      - Deutsche UNESCO-Kommission, Die Vereinten Nationen im Unterricht, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 4)
      - World Citizens Association, The World at the Crossroads, 1946 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, Co-ordination Committee for International Voluntary Work Camps
    - General. Reports, correspondence, and list of conferences and projects, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Handbook (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom. "Some Aspects of Non-Violent Resistance in Norway during the German Occupation " by Helga Stene. Typescript report, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Newsletters, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Pamphlets, 1932-1943 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Printed matter
      - Deutsche Stiftung fur Entwicklungsldnder, Entwicklungslander in Forschung und Lehre: 1959-1962 (Box-folder 12: 10)
      - Schairer, Reinhold, Aktivierung der Talente, 1957 (Box-folder 12: 11)
      - Schleberge, Erwin and Rolf Wiese, Schriften zum deutschen Kommunalrecht, 1975 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - United Nations. Interview with Mr. Adolf Ciborowski, Deputy Director for Research and Development, Center for Housing, Building and Planning, United Nations, relating to the UNDP Skopje project. Typescript, 1981 June 22-26 (Box-folder 12: 13)
- Sound Recordings, 1981-1986
  Contains 12 sound cassettes. Includes interview with Adolf Cibrowoski (use copy reference number: 83025_a_0000076_a01) and a recording of the Orgeon Nobel Laureate Symposium.
  - Interviews with Adolf Ciborowski, 1981 March - June (Box-folder 39: 1-10)
    Ten cassettes, labeled sides 1-20. It is not known whether the typescript interview with Adolf Ciborowski (box 12, folder 13) is a transcript of some or all of these recordings. Use copy reference number: 83025_a_0000076_a01
  - "Oregon Nobel Laureate Symposium, Linfield College,", 1986 February
    Two cassettes
    - "Yolanda King" (Box-folder 39: 11)
    - "Lawrence Klein, Czeslaw Milosz, Charles Townes" (Box-folder 39: 12)
- Incremental Materials
  - Biographical File, 1992-2000 (Box 13)
    Includes bibliographies, a finding aid for the Irwin Abrams collection at Antioch University, and a list of Nobel peace laureates that Abrams met throughout his lifetime. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Antioch College cermenoy, honorary doctorate, 1997 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - Archival collections, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Bibliographies, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Biographical statement, 2000 (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - List of Nobel peace laureates Abrams met, 1992 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Correspondence, 1918-2003 (Box 13-14)
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - Allaway, William H., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 13: 14)
    - Bowman, John E., 1973-1988 (Box-folder 13: 15)
    - Breitenbach, Diether, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 13: 16)
    - Brislin, Richard, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 13: 17)
    - Broda, Engelbert, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13: 18)
    - Curti, Merle, 1986-1994 (Box-folder 13: 19)
    - Danckwortt, Dieter, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 13: 20)
    - Fuller, Jon, 1975-1989 (Box-folder 13: 21)
    - Gatzke, Hans W., 1954, 1983 (Box-folder 13: 22)
    - Gerhard, Dietrich, 1962-1981 (Box-folder 13: 23)
    - Halsted, Henry, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 13: 24)
    - Harris, David, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 13: 25)
    - Hayden, Rose L., 1980-1982 (Box-folder 13: 26)
    - Henderson, Algo D., 1975-1986 (Box-folder 13: 27)
    - Hunter, Allan A., 1962, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 28)
    - Jack, Homer, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 13: 29)
      Includes writings by Homer Jack
    - Khalid, Mansour, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 13: 30)
    - Kuehl, Warren F., 1980-1987 (Box-folder 13: 31)
    - Lutz, Ralph H., 1960-1961 (Box-folder 13: 32)
    - Mancini, Federico, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 33)
    - Markert, Axel, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 34)
    - Mestenhauser, Josef A., 1981-1984 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Meulen, Jacob ter, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Pintasilgo, Maria de Lourdes, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Plank, Emma and Robert, 1963-1987 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Read, James, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Reisner, Konrad, 1990-2003 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Richardson, John, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 14: 7-8)
    - Thurber, Clancy, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 14: 9)
      Includes obituary. See also Evaluations, University of Oregon (Box 17, Folder 3).
    - Violich, Francis, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Wirzberger, Karl-Heinz, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - White, Cyrus E., 1918, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 14: 12)
      Includes copy of letter (1918) from Arthur Capper, Kansas Governor, to White. Includes letters from Suda L. Bane.
    - Wolfe, M. R., 1970-1975 (Box-folder 14: 13)
    - Woronoff, Jon, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978-2005 (Box 14-16)
    Includes typescripts, galley proofs, and printed copies. Arranged chronologically.
    - "The Impact of Antioch Education Through Experience Abroad,", 1978 February (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - "Some Reflections on Historical Research and International Exchange," in Research in Exchanges, conference proceedings, 1980 November (Box-folder 14: 16)
    - "Some Reflections On Historical Research and International Interchange,", 1980 November (Box-folder 14: 17)
      Prepared for the Conference on Research on International Exchange in Bonn, Germany
    - "The Challenge of Historic Preservation," for The Role of Architecture, the Tasks and the Responsibility of an Architect in Shaping the Human Environment, 1981 June (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - "The University Professor as Teacher, Some Reflections on the American Experience,", 1982 (Box-folder 14: 19)
    - "The Nobel Prize in Peace," galley proof, 1988 (Box-folder 14: 20)
    - Quote about Antioch College and educational exchange, 1989 (Box-folder 14: 21)
    - "Carl von Ossietzky and the First Nobel Peace Prize for Human Rights," for the Joint Annual Convention of the British International Studies Association and the International Studies Association, 1989 March-April (Box-folder 14: 22)
    - "Carl von Ossietzky Retrospective" in The Nobel Prize Annual 1989, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 23)
    - "Concepts of Peace in the Nobel Peace Prize,", 1990 September (Box-folder 14: 24)
    - "Conscience Against Violence,", 1991 (Box-folder 14: 25)
    - "The Nobel Prize in Peace" in The Nobel Prize Annual 1990, 1991 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - "The Quaker Peace Testimony and the Nobel Peace Prize,", 1991 May (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - "Je me souviens..." in International Peace Bureau Centenary Exhibition, circa 1992 (Box-folder 15: 3)
      Includes description of 1936 trip to Europe to research dissertation
    - "The Nobel Peace Prize" in The Nobel Peace Annual 1991, 1992 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - "The Many Meanings of the Nobel Peace Prize,", 1992 June (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - "Nobel Peace Laureate Christian L. Lange of Norway: Apostle of Concord,", 1992 June (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - "An American Quaker's Experience of Soviet Peacemaking,", 1992 September (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - "Christian Lous Lange, 'Apsotle of Concord,' Nobel Peace Prize Laureate" in Inter-Parliamentary Bulletin, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - "The Nobel Prize in Peace" in The Nobel Prize Annual 1992, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - "Chere Baronne et Amie: Letters of Alfred Nobel and Bertha von Suttner" in Die Waffen Nieder!, 1993 June (Box-folder 15: 10)
      Includes flyer for speaking engagement
    - "Heroines of Peace: The Nine Nobel Women," lecture flyer, 1993 June (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Lecture titles, 1993 July (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - "What's in a Name?", 1993 August (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - "The Nobel Peace Prize 1993," note, 1993 October (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - "The Odd Couple,", 1993 November (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - "'93 Novel Peace Prize Take a Chance on the Future,", 1993 December (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - "The Nobel Peace Prizes as Teaching Tools" in Magazine of History, Organization of American Historians, 1994 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - "Postage Stamps and Peace Education: The Nobel Peace Prize,", 1994 October-November and 1995 April (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - The Words of Peace: Selections from the Speeches of the Winners of the Nobel Peace Prize, edited by Abrams, 1995 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - "Henri Lafontaine (1854-1943)" in Inter-Parliamentary Bulletin, 1996 February (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - "Reflections on the First Century of the Nobel Peace Prize,", 2000 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Book review of The Nobel Peace Prize and the Laureates, 2002 April (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - "Why Senji Yamaguchi--A Survivor of Nagasaki--Should Win the Nobel Peace Prize,", 2005 February (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Academic Career and Peace Organizations File, 1932-1977 (Box 16-20)
    Includes correpondence, reports, papers, evaluations of study abroad programs, and newsletters related to Abrams' work as a professor and advocate for peace. Arranged alphabetically by name of organization or subject.
    - American Friends Sevice Committee (AFSC)
      - Pamphlets, 1940-1952, undated (Box-folder 16: 6-7)
      - Travel diary, 1946 (Box-folder 16: 8)
        Includes descriptions of Carrara and Marciaso, Italy; Berlin, Germany; Warsaw, Gora, Kozienice, Czerwokna, and Gdynia, Poland; and Geneva, Switzerland. See also American Friends Service Committee File, European trip to AFSC Work Camps (Box 2, Folder 27).
    - Antioch College
      - General, 1997, undated (Box-folder 16: 9)
      - Institute of Pacific Relations, Owen Lattimore, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 16: 10)
        Materials used in an Antioch course
      - Master of Arts program booklet, 1981 (Box-folder 16: 11)
        Includes note about Jose Ramos-Horta
      - Peace Corps, advance training program for Columbia, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 12)
    - Council on International Educational Exchange, 1985 (Box-folder 16: 13)
    - European Peace Historians, "Euro-Pax," Germany, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - Evaluations and consulting work
      Includes evaluations of study abroad programs
      - Hope College, Dubrovnik, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 15)
      - Houston Baptist College, 1966, undated (Box-folder 16: 16)
      - Pennsylvania State University, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 17: 1)
      - Study abroad programs, 1961 (Box-folder 17: 2)
      - University of Oregon, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 17: 3)
      - Upland College, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 17: 4)
      - Wittenberg University, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Ghosananda, Maha, nomination for Nobel Peace Prize, 1996 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Grawemeyer Award, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - Great Lakes College Association (GLCA)
      - Latin American Progam in Bogota, Columbia, report and poster, 1975 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      - Pamphlet, circa 1977 (Box-folder 17: 9)
      - Yugoslavia
        - American-Yugoslavia Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies, reports, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 17: 10-11)
        - American-Yugoslavia Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies, reports, (cont'd.), 1968-1970 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
        - Novi Sad program, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 18: 3)
        - Novi Sad, Town Planning Office, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 18: 4)
        - Papers and reports, 1966-1970, undated (Box-folder 18: 5)
        - Seminar memoranda and reports, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - "Ideas of Peace in History" project, USA/USSR, Charles Chatfield, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - International Peace Bureau, Geneva, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - International Society for Educational, Cultural and Scientific Interchanges
      - General, 1979-1988 (Box-folder 18: 9-10)
      - German-American exchange
        - General, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 1)
        - Bonn conference, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 19: 2-3)
          See also Subject File, German-American Conference on International Educational Exchange, Bonn, Germany (Box 5 and 6).
        - Wingspread conference, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 4-5)
    - Norwegian Nobel Institute
      - Poster, undated (Box-folder 19: 6)
      - Proposal to translate Pazifismus in Deutschland by Karl Holl, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Peace History Society, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 19: 8)
      Formerly council on Peace Research in History
    - Quaker relief in Poland, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Society for the Study of Internationalism, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 19: 10-11)
    - Stanford University
      - Class notes
        - "The Balkans Since 1800," David Harris, 1933 (Box-folder 20: 1)
        - Modern European History, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 20: 2)
      - History of Civilization textbook project, 1944-1952 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - United States Office of Education
      - Conference in Grubville, Missouri, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 4)
      - Higher Education Literature Search and Review Project, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 20: 5)
      - International education, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Conferences File, 1957-1998 (Box 21)
    Includes conference programs and proceedings, correspondence, and pamphlets. Arranged chronologically by date of conference.
    - 1957 March. "Americans at Work Abroad," Syracuse University, conference proceedings (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - 1972 October and 1973 February. World Campus Afloat, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - 1982 August-September. University Today Seminar, Dubrovnik, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - 1985 April. "Interchange/Interechange: Understanding Through International Exchange," (Box-folder 21: 4-5)
    - 1990 May. Vietnam Antiwar Movement Conference (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - 1992 September. "Peace Ideas and Movements in Russia and Western Peacemaking: Past and Present," Moscow (Box-folder 21: 7-8)
    - 1994 October. "The New Challenges of the 90's: One World Together," International Peace Bureau (Box-folder 21: 9)
      Includes draft of 1995 conference program
    - 1994 October-November. International Peace Research Association XV General Conference, Malta (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - 1995 September. Peace History Society Symposium, Canada (Box-folder 21: 11)
      In conjunction with the 18th International Congress of Historical Sciences
    - 1998 November. Third International Conference of Peace Museums (Box-folder 21: 12)
  - Subject File, 1900-2002 (Box 22-25)
    Includes correspondence, reports, conference materials, clippings, and printed matter related to subjects such as international education exchange, peace organizations, and World War II. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Berlin, 1950-1953, undated (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Ciborowski, Adolf, 1968-1980, undated (Box-folder 22: 2-3)
    - Committee of Soldiers' Mothers, Russia, circa 1991 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Conscientious objectors, 1951 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Duveneck, Frank B., 1944-1986 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Duveneck, Frank and Josephine, 1948-1984 (Box-folder 22: 7)
      Includes letter of Josephine Duveneck
    - "German Democratic Republic, 1950s," East Germany, 1947-1954 (Box-folder 22: 8-10)
    - German Democractic Republic, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Habitat, United Nations Conference on Human Settlements, 1976 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Hiroshima, 1995 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - History of exchange, 1964-1980 (Box-folder 23: 2)